Joe Wojak

- jwojak@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/joewojak
- https://github.com/jwwojak/jwwojak.github.io

I'm a technical writer with experience in creating documentation for external customers and internal engineering teams. I've managed large, established documentation libraries and created original documentation for new systems and services. My writing philosophy is to treat documentation like code. This means writing with open-source systems that accommodate community input and help reduce the documentation burden on developers.

Work Experience

Senior Technical Writer Spotify 2017–2022 Amplify R&D New York City

- Wrote developer-facing documentation for Spotify's internal system architecture. Content improved understanding among engineering teams about how to access and use services or how Spotify ad serving systems work.
- Wrote and revised training tutorials for engineers. Changes improved clarity, content adoption, and reduced confusion.
- Created and maintained *The Spotify Technical Writing Handbook*, a writing and style guide for developers.
- Recorded tutorial videos about how to write and use Spotify's internal documentation system.
- Founding member of a technical writing guild. The guild coordinated writing projects and promoted technical documentation at Spotify.
- Writing tools: MkDocs, Markdown, GitHub, Confluence, Coda, Loom (video), Google docs, sheets, slides.

Senior Technical Writer

Adobe Systems

2015-2017

Audience Manager

New York City

- Returned to Adobe to write and manage documentation for Audience Manager. Efforts brought neglected documentation up-to-date and reduced issue backlog.
- Created and reorganized documentation for the Marketing Cloud ID Service and the Marketing Cloud Device Co-Op. Efforts reduced support demands and allowed customers to work with these systems in a self-service manner.
- Helped developers write API documentation.
- Writing tools: XMetaL, Oxygen (DITA authoring systems), GitHub, Confluence.

Senior Technical Writer

Tapad

2013-2017

New York City

- First technical writer hired. Wrote customer-facing documentation for Tapad's probabilistic, cross-device ad targeting system.
- Worked with engineers to write API, Android, and iOS documentation.
- Writing tools: Confluence, Google docs.

- First technical writer hired. Tapad was a startup specializing in cross-device targeting/ad-serving.
- Created and managed the original set of internal and external documentation. Content used by internal staff and external customers.
- Worked with engineers to write API, Android, and iOS documentation.
- Writing tools: Confluence and Google products.

Education and Certifications

- MA, US History, University of Mississippi
- BA (Magna Cum Laude), History, University of Missouri

Writing Systems

Methodology: Written work follows *Darwin Information Typing Architecture* (DITA) documentation standards.
 Technologies: HTML editors, DITA/XML systems (Oxygen, XMetaL), Markdown, GitHub, MkDocs, Stack Overflow.
 Others: Confluence, Coda, Loom (videos), LucidChart, Google (docs, slides, sheets), JIRA, Trello, Slack.

Military Service

United States Army, Ft. Bragg, NC, honorable discharge.